本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译
王二川
抹茶咖啡
理奇
Richie!
翻译
吃货丁小七
-好准时  -您是我要找的律师吗
- Right on time. - Hey. You're the lawyer?
翻译
桑极客德
我叫罗恩·拉弗兰梅  很高兴认识你
Ron LaFlamme. Great to meet you.
翻译
机械章鱼X
好伙计  随便坐
All right, homeboy. Pop a squat.
在旗旁边签字吧
Start autographing by the flags.
翻译
七七
要签的文件可不少
Lot of paper to get through.
翻译
王大可
你觉得怎么样
So, what do you think?
什么怎么样
About?
珍妮  她很性感  对吧
Jeannie. She's pretty hot, right?
是  她很漂亮
Oh. Yeah. No, she's... she's very pretty.
当然
Yeah, she is.
还要击拳吗  好吧
Oh, we're doing that. OK.
时间轴
安安
彼得和我说  你是第一次接触这些
So yo, Peter tells me you're popping your cherry with this.
时间轴
sOF
那我给你说明下
So let me just walk you through it.
你现在在签的这份文件
That stuff you're signing gives you
是注资兑现票据
the convertible note for funding
也是你和彼得·格里高利
and establishes you and Peter Gregory
同为'魔笛手'公司的董事会成员的证明
as the board members of Pied Piper,
公司注册地为特拉华州
incorporated in the state of Delaware.
好吧  为什么是特拉华州
OK. Why Delaware?
你有钱  我也有  我是律师  而你不是
Rich, Rich. Lawyer, not lawyer.
听我的
I got you.
你的铁杆粉丝  彼得·格里高利
So, Peter Gregory, big fan of you.
邀请你参加他的长袍派对了  对吗
He invited you to his toga party, right?
这次盛况空前  佛罗·里达也去
That's a big deal. Flo Rida's gonna be there.
-你喜欢佛罗·里达吗  -应该会很不错
- You like Flo Rida? - Should be fun.
-喜欢  我去过很多次...  -看这把吉他
- Yeah, I went to a lot... - See this guitar?
校对
桑极客德
谷歌的创始人谢尔盖和拉里在上面签名了
Sergey and Larry from Google signed it.
校对
王小麦
两人都签了  在这
Both of them. Right there.
'魔笛手'
So, Pied Piper.
彼得也给你们这压缩算法投资了啊
You're one of Peter's compression plays, huh?
"也给"  他投资了多少个
Uhh, one of? How many does he have?
也不多  六个还是八个吧
Not too many. Like six or eight.
好吧  为什么会有这么多
OK. Why are there so many?
海龟一次要产非常多的卵
You know how sea turtles have a shit-ton of babies
因为绝大部分小海龟还没爬回海里就死了
because most of them die on their way down to the water?
彼得只是希望确保
Peter just wants to make sure
花的钱能物有所值
that his money makes it to the ocean.
你好像应对得还不错
But it seems like you got your shit together.
很多到这来的人
A lot of these guys come in here
做的一手好工程
and they can do all of the engineering stuff
可他们一心扑在技术上
but they get all hung up on technicalities.
连公司愿景是什么都说不清楚
They can't just tell you what their vision for the company is.
那些家伙真没用
Those guys are so fucked.
就好比大脑的左右半球  缺一不可
It's like you need both halves of the brain, right?
比如乔布斯和沃兹尼亚克  "硬和阳"
The Jobs and the Wozniak. The Ying and the Yang.
应该是读作"阴"
Oh. I think it's "Yin".
-"阴"  -对
- "Yin"? - Yeah.
-"阴"和"烟"  -不  是阴和阳
- Like "Yin and Yan?" - No. Like Yin and Yang.
不  就是"硬和阳"  是反义词
No. It's Ying and Yang, they're opposites.
来说说看  '魔笛手'是个啥
So, Pied Piper, drop it on me. What is it?
一开始是个音乐应用
Well, we started off as a music app.
-真土  -是挺糟糕
- Yuck. - Yeah. Gross. Ugh.
但我们之后就做了调整
But we've, uh, we've pivoted since then.
调整成什么样
Uh-oh. To what?
所有的媒体  音频  视频和元数据
Well, our Weissman scores are consistently high across all media,
我们的压缩评分都很高
audio, video, meta-data.
其实也不是
Actually, that's not true.
编码3D视频方面还需要改进
We've had some trouble encoding 3D video.
我认为应该是像素值的变化
I think it's because the pixels change value differently
与传统模式不同...
than conventional...
原创翻译  双语字幕
第
一
季
第
四
集
硅
谷
视效&后期
冰冰爱尖尖
好好看看这个流程图  哥们
Just look at the flow diagram, dude.
不  滤波器组是预测环的一部分
No, the filter bank is part of the prediction loop.
总监
面条打包子
你在说什么  这可是无损压缩
What are you talking about, this is lossless compression.
大头  那时候你也在场
Oh, hey, Big Head, you were there.
理查德为什么用离散式弦转换滤波器组
Why did Richard use a DCT filter bank?
我也不大确定  理查德解释过
Not really sure. Richard tried to explain some of this stuff
但大部分我都听不明白
but a lot of it I didn't really understand,
所以只能点头微笑
so I'd kinda just nod and smile, you know?
那你至少帮我们想想
Can you at least help us
这奇葩的离散傅立叶转换蜘蛛网是什么意思
figure out this insane DFT spider web he's using?
哥们  这些东西你懂哪个
Dude, do you understand any of this?
我吃了鱼
I eat the fish.
我知道你吃了鱼
I understand you eat the fish.
但你把鱼肉吃完后
But when you clean the fish
不能把鱼头  内脏什么的留在水槽里
you can't leave the fish head and guts and shit in the sink.
会让整间房子闻起来像个毒饵站
Because the whole house smells like a bait station.
你得把这些丢进垃圾桶  然后丢到屋外去
So you gotta put it in the trash and then take the trash out.
你明白吗
Do you understand?
是的  我吃了鱼
Yes. I eat the fish.
你妈蛋
Motherfuck!
自己的公司都说不明白
Do you know how awkward it is
你们知道有多尴尬吗
to not be able to describe your own company?
比如我创建了'魔笛手'  你也知道
Like, I built Pied Piper and you could see it
但是我没法跟你讲明白
but I can't really describe to you what it is
即使我大概知道自己在干嘛
even though I kind of know where I'm going.
你知道我们放弃了自己的软件
You do realize we quit working on our own apps
来给你工作  对吧
to work for you, right?
你不该比"大概知道"强点吗
Shouldn't you more than "Kind of know where you're going?"
首席执行官不就是干这个的吗
Because that's basically what the CEO does.
我知道
I do.
基本上吧
Sort of.
这就像是想给别人指路
OK, it's like trying to tell someone how to get somewhere,
虽然你也不知道确切地址
even though you don't really know the exact address. Right?
你能怎么做呢
Like, how do you do that?
你又不能直接说"去榆树街415号"
Because you can't just say "Go to 415 Elm Street,"
因为你也不知道那是哪里
because you don't even know what that is. Right?
你就得说  沿着大路一直走
So you have to say, you know, "Go straight down that big road
看到那诡异的东西就右拐
and take a right at the weird thing."
但又说不明白诡异的东西是什么
But, you can't describe what that weird thing is
因为你只知道它诡异
because you just know it as a weird thing, you know,
它一直存在于你的脑海中
in your head. You always have.
你脑袋里那个诡异的东西是动脉瘤吗
Is that weird thing in your head an aneurysm?
理查德  我来回顾一下
Richard, I'm just gonna recap for a second,
你拒绝了千万巨款
um, you turned down ten million dollars
转而开发一个
to be able to develop something that you,
你身为领导
as the head of the company,
都讲不明白的公司
can't even describe to another human being?
我只是想激励你一下
I say this only to motivate you.
我奉命把你从
OK, so I have been instructed to remove you
分配给'纽核力'项目的雇员列表里删除
from the list of employees assigned to the Nucleus project.
你不会再收到任何与'纽核力'相关的信息
You will no longer receive any Nucleus related communications,
文件报告  或参加任何'纽核力'会议
uh, file reports, or attend any Nucleus meetings.
有什么问题吗
Any questions?
没有  说得很清楚了
Uh, no. That's... That's pretty clear.
很好
Great.
我会分配到其他项目吗
Am I being reassigned to something else?
据我所知不会  暂时不会
Not that I am aware of. At this time. No.
那是说我被解雇了吗
Wait, so then am I being fired?
我签的是三年的合同
Because I have a three year contract
而且我的股票期权...
and my stock options...
没人被解雇  好吗
Nobody is being fired. OK?
合同就是合同
Look, a contract is a contract.
你签署了合同
You know. You've got a contract.
我也签署了合同  大家都签了合同
And I've got a contract. We all have contracts.
在'互利'  大家都尊重合同
And-and here at Hooli, contracts are honored.
无论是你的  我的
Um... Yours and mine.
还是大家的合同
Everybody's. So, um...
我说清楚了吗
have I made that perfectly clear?
是的  清楚了
Yeah, no. That's clear.
但是  我明天来上班的时候
But, when I come into work tomorrow,
应该做什么呢
what do I... do?
这一点暂时还不清楚
That is unclear. At this time.
不该只穿一条内裤和一张床单就来的
Shoulda worn more than my underwear and a bed sheet.
-还穿内裤  真娘炮  -我同意
- Underwear? Pussy. - Yeah. I'm with him.
这种派对就该让蛋蛋放风
This is the type of evening that requires free-balling.
我也要把内裤脱掉
I'm gonna take my underwear off too.
理查德  你来了
Richard! Hey, you made it!
彼得今天见了拉弗兰梅  签署了文件
So Peter met with LaFlamme today and signed the paperwork,
也就是说'魔笛手'正式启动了
which means Pied Piper is officially launched.
为什么你不告诉我
Uh, why didn't you tell me about
彼得还投资了其他压缩软件
all the other compression plays Peter was seeding?
什么  没有啊  因为你不用操心这些
What? No... Because it's nothing you need to worry about.
那些公司都没有你的远见
Because none of those other companies have your vision.
-远见  -没错
- My vision? - Exactly.
说到这个  彼得非常希望你周五
Speaking of which, Peter really wants you to come in on Friday
能来讨论一下发展走向
to chat about big picture stuff.
大致陈述一下你的愿景
You know, lay out your vision in broad strokes.
大致走向  愿景...
Broad strokes... for the vision of the...
我们都知道'魔笛手'是一个压缩工具
Well, uh, Pied Piper is compression and we all know that.
这点不用多说
So we don't need to talk about that...
但我可以多说  因为我是首席执行官
but I could because I'm the CEO.
'魔笛手'将数据
Pied Piper takes the data...
缩小  变小
and... smaller. To smaller.
当然还有其他的
And, also, there's more.
数据的整体压缩...
It compresses the data overall...
抱歉失陪一下  周五见  汤姆
Yeah, I... Excuse me. See you Friday. Hi Tom.
理查德  悠着点  伙计
Richard, pace yourself, buddy.
我真希望现在还是罗马时代
You know, I wish this was Roman times. You know?
那个时候生活简单多了
Life was simpler back then.
对你来说更简单  我就只能当奴隶了
Simpler for you. I would have been a slave.
还有时间
There's still time.
这身打扮不错  哪里弄的
Cool costume. Where'd you get it?
我的床上
Uh, my bed.
你真搞笑
You're funny!
我叫布鲁克  这是我朋友阿纳斯塔西娅
I'm Brooke and this is my friend Anastasia.
你好
Hi.
-你好  -你们好吗
- Hi. - What's up, guys?
所以  你是怎么认识彼得·格里高利的
So-so-so, how do you know Peter Gregory?
因为工作的关系
Oh, through work.
我们是演员
We're actresses.
-真酷  -哪一种演员呢
- Cool. - Uh, what type of actressing you work?
我们现在就在工作
Oh, we're working right now.
我们公司为派对提供暖场演员
Our startup sources actors to parties to liven things up
主动搭讪并对派对来宾表示兴趣
and get into conversations with guests and be interested in them.
真厉害
Oh. Neat.
这里还有谁是被雇来的
So, uh, who else is paid to be here?
长相七分以上的都是我们的人
Pretty much anyone that's over a seven is with us,
三分以下的都是来宾
and anyone that's under a three is a guest.
这工作很有意思  而且
It's a really fun job. Plus,
我能跟我男朋友一块儿工作
um, I get to work with my boyfriend.
各位来宾  准备好狂欢了吗
Yo, yo, party people, y'all ready to get crazy?
那是佛罗·里达吗
Is that Flo Rida?
不清楚
No idea.
你们准备好进入高潮了吗
Y'all ready to take this party to a whole 'nother level?
到时间跟我们的流氓头子
It's time to meet the original OG Gangster,
吸金大亨见面了
cash money mobster.
热烈欢迎我的拜把子
Y'all put your hands together for my brother!
最碉堡  最炫酷的
The illest, the chillest,
彼得·格里高利大帝
Emperor of Rome, big Pete Gregory!
他最碉堡最炫酷吗
He is the illest and the chillest?
彼得·格里高利大帝
Big Pete Gregory!
谢谢  佛罗·里达
Thank you, Florida.
欢迎来到彼得·格里高利基金会
Welcome to the Peter Gregory Foundation's
第四次年度爱心狂欢会
fourth annual orgy of caring.
前三次都不错
The first three were fine.
希望你们玩得开心
I hope that you enjoy the party.
后面还有个吧台
There is a second bar in back
排队的人少点
where the line is much shorter.
谢谢  我说完了
Thank you. I'm finished.
我有点跟不上他的节奏
That was very abrupt.
-所以这是个说唱音乐会  -没错
- So this is a rap concert? - Yep.
我靠  快看埃利希
Holy shit, look at Erlich!
他妹的是怎么跑上去的
How the fuck did he get up there?
看看人家  那才是我想要的
Man. See, that's what I wish I had.
我觉得自己没
It's like, I don't have any...
-没戏  -没戏  就是这个
- Game. - Game, yes! That's it.
我总觉得自己缺点什么东西
You know, I always knew I was missing something
后来有人告诉我有戏是什么意思
and then someone explained to me the concept of game,
我记得很清楚
I remember very distinctly thinking,
"我就是没有戏"
"That's what I don't have. Game."
不好意思
Sorry.
未知来电
-喂  -你好吗  土豪里奇
- Hello? - What's up, Richie Rich?
真高兴昨晚见到你了
Great seeing you last night, buddy.
我就是想通知你我已经让同事
Just wanted you to know I had my associate
按我们说的起草好文件了
draft up everything like we talked about and it is all good.
我刚把董事会决议发给你
Just emailed you the board consent
包括对新董事会成员的任命
which appoints your new board member.
打印出来签好字
So just print it, sign it,
再让格里高利签字就搞掂了
get it to Gregory to sign and it is donezo.
什么  新董事会成员
Uh, new board member, what?
都在PDF文件里  自己看
It's in the PDF, you'll see.
小家伙  我得挂了  给我灌肠的来了
All right, homey, I gotta go. My enema guy is here.
加里  欢迎
Gary! Namaste!
魔笛手公司变更了董事会成员
Pied Piper Incorporated amended board of directors:
理查德·亨德里克斯  彼得·格里高利
Richard Hendricks, Peter Gregory...
埃利希·巴赫曼
Erlich Bachman?
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
睡美人起床了吗
Is sleeping beauty awake?
看来起床了
Yes, she is.
来  我给你弄了点填肚子的
Oh, boy. Here, I brought you something for your stomach.
对了  橙汁里加了伏特加
Be forewarned, the orange juice has vodka in it.
以酒解酒
Little hair of the dog.
昨晚到底发生了什么  你还记得吗
What exactly happened last night, from your side?
是我们  理查德  最棒的是
We happened, Richard. And the best part is,
我们想什么时候重温都可以
we can relive it whenever we want to.
我们就像大脑的左右半球
We're two halves of the same brain!
你是我的另一半
Whoa! You complete me!
你敢再说这个  听懂了吗
Don't ever say that again! Do you understand me?
小心我打死你
I will beat the shit out of you.
别拿那玩意拍我
Yo, yo, get that camera out my face.
-别这样  -别拿那玩意拍我
- Come on, Mr... OK, OK. - Get the camera out my face!
-看这段  -我邀请这位胖...
- Look at this part. - I'm asking this fat,
美男
beautiful man
由上帝和佛罗·里嘚儿
in front of God and the Flo Rider
还有这满身可卡因的诡异雕塑见证
and this white, weird cocaine statue
-我邀请你加入'魔笛手'董事会  -好
- to be on the Pied Piper board of directors. - Yes!
-绝对没问题  -他答应了
- A thousand times, yes! - He's doin' it!
-来握个手  -说定了
- Shake on it. - It's a deal.
-不要  -还有  咱要拍部'魔笛手'的纪录片
- Oh, no. - Plus, we have this for the Pied Piper documentary
这段得加进去
that we're eventually gonna make.
咱是在创造历史  搭档
We're making history together, partner.
你在学乔布斯穿衣吗
Are you dressed like Steve Jobs?
有吗
Oh, am I?
看来我和他的
Well, I suppose Steve and I
审美眼光很接近
always have shared a similar aesthetic.
帮个忙呗
Little help?
好吧
Oh. OK.
-给你  -谢了  伙计
- Here you go. - Thanks, man.
抱歉没扔上来  关节有炎症
Sorry about the throw. Bursitis.
你们在这开会吗
Uh, so, you guys having a meeting up here?
不算是
No. Not exactly.
我们现在没工作可做
We're all currently... unassigned.
你呢
How about you?
我也是
Yeah. Unassigned.
也没啥
That's cool.
你怎么能让埃利希进董事会
How could you put Erlich on the board?
你想什么呢
What were you thinking?
你不能让公司里的人进董事会
You don't put someone inside the company on the board.
这样他和彼得就能投票把你赶出去了
Then he and Peter Gregory can vote you out.
要找个你能信任的外人  比如你妈
Yeah. You gotta find an outsider you trust. Like your Mom.
我宁可要埃利希也不要我妈  背后捅刀子的贱人
I'd put Erlich on the board before my mom. Backstabbing bitch.
我喝多了好吗
Guys, I was drunk, OK?
我昨晚还和吉尔弗约尔半开玩笑地说
You know, I half-jokingly said to Gilfoyle last night:
"理查德好像要给埃利希吹箫哎"
"It looks like Richard is going to suck Erlich's dick."
跟现在一比也不算什么了
But that would be reasonable compared to this.
理查德  能说句话吗
Richard, um, could I speak to you?
好吧
OK. Yeah.
他是我见过最没劲的人
He's the least cool guy I've ever met.
我听说了昨晚的事
I heard about what's been happening.
我得承认我有点失望
I have to say, I'm a little disappointed.
我也不知道我当时在想什么
Yeah, I don't... I don't know what I was thinking.
是啊
Yes. I mean, um,
为什么没请我去派对呢
is there a reason I wasn't invited to the party?
难道我不是团队一员吗
Is there some sense that I'm not part of the gang?
什么  贾里德
What? Uh, Jared.
当然是  我只是不小心忘了
Of course not. It was just an oversight.
我们自己还在犹豫去不去
I mean, we weren't even sure if we were gonna go.
那边什么样
Uh-huh. And what was it like there?
有低酒精饮料吗
Were there gelatin shots?
没有  很蠢也很吵
No. No, uh, it was stupid and loud.
说实话  幸亏你没去
Uh, honestly, you're better off.
也许吧  昨晚还不错
I suppose. I had a fine night.
我吃了菠菜芝士
I... I had some palak paneer
看了部讲利比亚的纪录片
and I watched a documentary about Liberia.
结果醒来就听到了这个
But then I woke up to this, um, unexpected development.
你真想让埃利希进董事会吗
Do you...do you really want Erlich on the board?
-我是支持你的  -不想  一点也不
- Because I'll support you... - No. I don't. At all.
我就是喝多了
I was just drunk.
我不知道该怎么办
I don't know how to get out of it.
我怎么跟彼得·格里高利说啊
I mean, what am I going to say to Peter Gregory?
你不在上面签字
Well, if you don't sign the documents,
也不给彼得·格里高利看
and you don't give them to Peter Gregory,
不就没问题了  多简单
then it won't happen. Simple as that.
真的  我  太好了
Really? I... Wow. OK.
松了口气  谢谢你  贾里德
That is a relief, Jared. Thanks.
幸亏有你在
I'm...I'm glad you're around.
再有派对时别忘了我就好了
Well, keep that in mind for future parties.
有时我们会忘了你在这
Honestly, sometimes we forget you're here.
快出来  到房子后边
You guys, company photo time
照公司全家福了
out back. Let's go!
吉尔弗约尔  别站中间
Uh, Gilfoyle, OK, off to the center a little bit.
你就爱当焦点  不不不不
Like your personality. No, no, no, no.
迪尼希  别系扣子  你得邋遢点
Dinesh, leave it unbuttoned. We want you to look like shit.
弄出"成名之前"的效果
Makes for a better "Before" Photo.
但你穿的是正装
But you're wearing a jacket.
当然  因为我是天才营销大师
Yeah, because I'm the genius marketer.
不跟你们码农似的
I'm not a code freak like you guys.
而且我穿了凉鞋  所以还是很反传统的
Besides, I'm wearing sandals so I am iconoclasting a little bit.
很好  贾里德  你穿的什么破马甲
Oh, good. Jared. Ugh. What the fuck is with that vest?
你站这  这样就显得你是最后加入的
Right over here. As if you're sort of a late addition
没有亲身见证公司成立的伟大时刻
that may not stick around for the entire duration of the company.
然后理查德  你在这  我们的大明星
And then, Richard. There you go. The man of the hour.
很好  我们拍几张合照
OK. We'll take a few like this,
然后  我和理查德再单独合影
and then... just Richard and I.
因为到头来
Because at the end of the day,
人们只想看见董事会高层的尊容
people only want to see a picture of the board members.
这个  其实吧
It... Actually, it's, um...
你不会进董事会的
you're not gonna be a board member.
啥玩意
What?
我的五年合同已经到了第三年了
I'm in year three of a five year deal
马特  你还剩三年是吧
and, Matt, you got what, like three years left?
我们都被互利招募进来
Yeah. We all got acquired by Hooli,
而当我们没法融入进去时  就没活干了
when we didn't work out, none of us got reassigned.
因为嘉文认为在他的日式管理模式下
Because Gavin believes in this Japanese form of management
没活干就是最大的耻辱了
where not being assigned is the most shameful outcome.
感觉是有点别扭
Yeah, it does feel uncomfortable.
看着吧  过个一两周  你就麻木了
Nah. Give it a week or two, you'll get, like, numb to it.
那你们还来上班干嘛
Well, why are you guys still coming in?
休憩与评估
Rest and vest.
对哈  为了得到全额补偿
Oh... Because in order to fully vest your options,
你们要待到合同结束
you've gotta wait until your contracts are up.
-我懂了  -懂得够慢的
- I get it. - You catch on slow.
跟我们很对路
You'll fit right in here.
吃饭吧  艾尔卡米诺那边的阿贝家如何  我开车
Lunch? Arby's on El Camino? I'll drive.
[著名三明治连锁店]
别  走着去吧  走着更慢
No, let's walk. It'll take longer.
总得过得充实些  对吧
Gotta do something to fill the day, right?
我当时喝醉了  你利用了这个机会
I was drunk! You took advantage of me!
他俩真是火力全开啊
Man, they are really going at it.
这个  昨晚上的姑娘们如何
So, um... last night, what was the girl situation?
-小声点  -我为你这公司放弃了多少
- Shhh. - And after all I've given up for this company.
你倒说说你放弃什么了
Oh, what have you given up?
迪尼希的软件我占一成股份
I owned ten percent of Dinesh's app,
吉尔弗约尔的软件也一样
ten percent of Gilfoyle's app.
这都是潜在的收入来源啊
Multiple potential streams of income.
更别提你公司里所有的员工
Not to mention that a hundred percent of the team
全都是我招进这间房子里的
that you have, were all guys that I recruited for this house.
-我没功劳也有苦劳吧  -你有回报啊
- That must be worth something to me. - It is!
就是魔笛手的一成股权
Ten percent of Pied Piper!
我为此先行投入了  你没听错
For which I forewent, yes, that's a real word,
-一百万美刀  -是吗
- one million dollars. - Mmm.
我支持你  理查德  我相信你
I supported you, Richard. I bet on you.
而你的回报却是许诺我
And now you're just gonna give
进入董事会之后  现在又反悔了
me a seat on the board, only to retract that offer?!
我根本就不记得那么说过
I can't even remember doing that!
是吗  那你记得
Oh, really? Well, do you
我录下来的这个混蛋说过的话吗
remember this particular dick-bag I got on video?
你就是说过
Because you did.
没完了你
Put it away.
马上给你看
It's right here.
该死
Goddammit.
视频我看过了
I've seen the video.
我进错文件夹了  你等一会儿
It's the wrong album, just give me a sec...
可恶  去你妈的  你说过让我进董事会
You know what? Fuck it! You offering me a position
现在又出尔反尔
on this board and reneging it
这充分证明了你既没有远见
is a perfect example of you having no vision,
也没种  更没戏
no balls and no game.
也许他确实给他吹箫了
Maybe he did blow him.
好一出爱恨情仇  太有张力了
Well, love and hate... it's all passion.
如果你要开的就是这种破公司
And if that's the kind of company you wanna run,
那随你便
well, then, fine.
你自己耍去吧  我才不会帮你
God help you. 'Cause I sure as hell ain't.
你干什么呢
Uh, what are you doing?
你效忠了别人
You give your loyalty to somebody...
-我帮你脱  -手拿开
- Let me help you. - Don't touch!
-我自己脱得下来  -好吧
- I can do it myself. - All right.
老子不脱了  该死
I just put it back on. Goddammit!
麻烦你再念一遍
OK. Read that back to me.
魔笛手的使命就是
"Pied Piper's mission is
以其独一无二的压缩算法
to bring its unique compression algorithm
-应对各种  -想住在我这
- to a variety..." - One thing you should know
有件事你得清楚
about living in this house
那就是我绝对禁止嗑药过量
is I do not tolerate substance abuse.
也不准酗酒和背叛好兄弟
There's no drinking and lying in this house.
我应该把这一点
I should have made that
跟现在住在这里的某些人说得更清楚些的
more clear to some of the current residents.
比如这位  不用管他
Like this one. Don't mind him.
等他的公司屎尿满地之后他很快就会搬走了
He'll be gone soon when his company cakes its pants.
尤根  希望你能
Hopefully, Jurgen, you'll be
给这房子带来些积极向上的东西
able to bring a more positive element to the house.
让我带你看看房间
Let me show you the room I'm offering.
他的一些员工还住在这
Some of his stuff is still in there,
但正如我所说  他们很快就会搬走
but, as I mentioned, it will soon be gone.
等他的公司屎尿满地之后
Once his company cakes its pants.
没关系  深呼吸一下
It's OK. Just take a breath.
没关系  我很好  我们...
It's fine. I'm fine. Uh, we just...
先把这个做完吧  再念一遍
Let's get through this. OK, so, read this back to me.
-"魔笛手的使命..."  -伙计们
- "Pied Piper's mission..." - Hey, guys.
希望你们不要介意  前门没关
Hope you don't mind, the front door was just open.
大头  怎么了
Hi, Big Head. What's up?
没怎么  我只是闲了一天
Honestly? Nothing. I've just been sitting around all day.
没有事情做  感觉很奇怪
Not working. It's weird, you know?
你们怎么样了
So, what's up with you guys?
我们只是在...
We're just sort of...
我们在准备和彼得·格里高利的重要会议
We're getting ready for this big Peter Gregory meeting.
我们...我们还有好多事情要做
And we have... we have a lot of work to do, so...
很好  太好了
Cool. Very cool.
你知道吗  理查德  讽刺的是
You know, Richard, the irony
如果你接受了那一千万
is that if you had taken the ten million,
你现在就会带着大把的钱在休息
you'd be kicking back with a
而我在工作
ton of money right now and I'd still be working.
但你没有  所以现在是我无所事事
But you didn't, obviously. And now I've got nothing to do,
坐享收入  而你却忙的四脚朝天
I'm rolling in it, and you're working your ass off.
生活就是这么有意思  不是吗
Life's funny isn't it?
你们想去阿贝家
You guys want to walk to Arby's,
吃点东西  踢会儿毽子吗
maybe grab a bite, play a little hacky sack?
好吧  我该回去工作了
Yeah. I should probably get back to work, anyway.
确切说也不算工作
I mean, not work, exactly, I don't...
我并没有事情做  但我还是得回互利去了
I don't work. But, you know, just get back to Hooli.
整天坐在那儿无所事事却有大笔收入
Sit around all day and get paid a bunch of money to do nothing.
感觉真奇怪
Weird.
准备好了吗
You ready?
知道自己都要说什么吗  要先跟我试试吗
You know what you're going to say? You want to run it by me?
不用  我能搞定  去他的埃利希
No, no. I got this. Fuck Erlich.
我拒绝了一千万美元就为了建这个公司
You know, I turned down ten million dollars to build this thing.
你想要远见  我就给你看看什么是远见
You want vision, I will show you fucking vision.
我喜欢你愤怒的这一面
I like this new angry side to you.
呆在愤怒的人旁边会让我觉得放松
Being around angry people relaxes me,
因为我能明确我的立场
because I know where I stand.
该死  我觉得好像有东西卡在我的牙里了
Oh, shoot. I think I got something stuck in my teeth.
我得去一下洗手间看一下
I'm just gonna go to the bathroom, check it out.
马上就回来
I'll be back in a sec.
理查德  我是贾里德  你还好吗
Richard, it's Jared. Are you OK?
老兄  这是...怎么了
Hey buddy, what's... what's going on here?
我觉得我牙齿上有东西
I thought I had something in my teeth,
但当我检查牙齿时  我像这样看着镜子
but when I looked over, right? I looked in the mirror like this,
我的裤子撞到了洗手台
uh, my pants they hit the countertop,
裤子上就会沾上水的  对不对
and it must have some water on there, right?
我的裤子上就会湿一块
so I got a spot on my pants,
看起来就像我尿裤子了一样
kinda looked like I pissed myself like a big baby.
所以我就脱下了我的裤子
So what I did was, I just took off all my pants
把它放进水里让它全部浸湿
and I put it in the water just to make it all completely wet.
这样我想就没人会注意到了
You know, that way I figured no one would really notice.
至少会不那么糟  一切都在掌握之中
So, you know, it wouldn't be as bad. I've got it under control.
我能搞定的  没事
I've sorted it out. We're good.
所以你觉得这样会不那么糟
Yes. So you felt this wouldn't look as bad.
-我明白了  -没错
- Understood. - Yeah.
但是  理查德
But, Richard? Um...
穿成这样
Consider that maybe this
是不是不太适合参加会议呢
might not be the best choice for the meeting?
是啊  天呐
Yeah. Holy...
我这是在做什么
What the fuck am I doing?
我不能穿成这样去开会
I can't go like this to the meeting.
贾里德  我根本没有远见
Jared. I have no vision.
不  你有
Yes, you do.
-我相信你  -我真的一点远见都没有
- I believe in you... - No, no, I literally have no vision.
我现在满脑子星星和漩涡  什么也看不到
All I see is stars and swirls. I cannot see right now.
好吧  先把裤子穿上
OK, let's get your pants on.
贾里德  理查德  你们在里面吗
Jared? Richard? Are you in there?
海上天气不太好
Hey, there's some weather over the ocean
所以彼得想赶快开始  你们准备好了吗
so Peter would love to get started. Are you guys ready?
是的  没事  马上就来
Yep. All good. Be there in a jiffy.
好的
OK.
贾里德  我趴在洗手间的地毯上
Jared, I'm on a carpet in a bathroom.
是的  我知道当一个人恐慌发作的时候
Yeah, OK. Um, I know this isn't the best thing to say
说这个不太合适
to someone having a panic attack,
但是我们需要抓紧时间了
but we need to hurry here.
-还好吗  -好多了
- Doing OK? - Yes, much better.
没有  更糟了
Nope. Worse.
理查德  如果你知道什么
Richard, you're gonna
对你最好  那你就该听我的
listen to me if you know what's good for you.
-埃利希  -也许成为董事会成员
- Erlich. - I may have been wrong about being a board member
还有成为我们之间的
and I may be wrong about
史蒂夫·乔布斯都是我想错了
being the Steve Jobs in our relationship.
但我很确定  你就是史蒂夫·沃兹尼亚克
But I do know this, you are the Steve Wozniak.
而沃兹不应该单独参加这样的会议
And no Woz should go into a meeting like that alone.
-不  事实上  -所以
- No. Actually... - So if
让我进去陪你  我不说话
you'll just let me come in, then I won't speak.
我只是认为需要有个会关照你的人
And I just think you should have somebody in there
陪你进去
who will actually have your back.
好的  我  埃利希  我愿意让你进去
OK. No, I... Erlich, I want you to be in there.
好的  等等  什么
OK... Wait, what?
是的  我还需要你来讲解
Yes, and I need you to do all the talking.
因为我觉得如果我来讲
Because I feel like if I
我会吐在彼得·格里高利身上
do I'm gonna puke all over Peter Gregory.
好  好的
Oh, OK. Wow.
比我想的容易  全部我来讲
That was easier than I... All the talking?
埃利希  你也来啦
Oh, Erlich, you're here too?
好了  进来吧伙计们
OK. Come on in, guys.
我想我还是留在这吧
Um, I'm going to stay here, I think.
因为我看起来怪怪的
Because I look absurd.
是的  好吧
Yeah. Yeah, OK.
-所以你打算怎么说  -我不知道
- So what are you going to say? - Fuck, I don't know.
现在的用户需要能即时访问
Today's user wants access to all of their files
他们所有设备里的所有文件
from all their devices instantly.
所以云功能才会这么火爆
That's why cloud-based is the Holy Grail.
'碉堡盒'已经先声夺人了
Now Dropbox is winning,
但是在声音和视频文件方面
but when it comes to audio and video files,
它瞬间就变成了'弱爆盒'
they might as well be called Dripbox.
使用我们的平台  魔笛手的用户
Using our platform, Pied Piper users
可以将他们的所有文件
would be able to compress all their files
压缩至可以瞬间获取的大小
to the point where they truly can access them instantly.
我们控制渠道
We control the pipe,
他们只是使用
they just use it.
这就是理查德·亨德里克斯脑中的公司远见
That's the vision in Richard Hendricks' head.
有趣
Sure.
听起来不错
Sounds fine.
我收到了一封罗恩·拉弗兰梅发来的邮件
Oh, I received an email from Ron LaFlamme
上面说这位先生
saying that this gentleman
将会成为第三位董事会成员
is going to be our third board member?
是的  是的
Yes. Yes.
这些事都是埃利希帮我的  他很有才
Uh, Erlich helped me with all this stuff. He's very talented.
我需要他成为我的合伙人
I need him as a partner.
好的
Fine.
现在你们可以走了
It's OK for you to leave now.
好的
All right, OK.
等等  这是你和盖文·贝尔森吗
Wait, is that you and Gavin Belson?
是的  那是张老照片
Yes. It's an old photograph.
你们是朋友吗
Were you guys friends?
我曾经那么认为
I thought so.
再见
Good-bye.
进展如何
How'd it go?
棒极了  我是说
That was amazing. I mean,
就像是我脑子里想的那样  但是更清晰
that was like everything in my head but, like, clear.
你是临场发挥的吗
Did you just make that up on the spot?
是啊  我们也许应该写下来
Yeah. We should probably write some of it down.
是啊  听着  我实话实说
Yeah. Well, look. I gotta be honest,
我无法形容这有多重要
I mean, I can't tell you how much this means.
尽管我对你犯了混  你还是帮了我
You really saved my ass even after I was such a dick to you.
-你们和好了  -我还能怎样呢  理查德
- You're making up! - What else could I do, Richard?
你是我的沃兹尼亚克
You're my Wozniak.
我会永远当你的
And I will always be...
妈了个
Motherfu...
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为